Guide to the Frank Espada photographs and papers, 1946-2010 and undated, bulk 1964-2000 RL.00367
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Puerto Rican Diaspora, 1965-1989 and undated; 30 Linear Feet 41 boxes Approximately 12,323 items
  - New York, 1965-1989; 3771 items
    - Contact Sheets and Work Prints, 1974-1989; 3702 items
      - Work prints: Manhattan Valley (folder 2 of 3), 1981; 69 items (Box 35, Folder 9)
      - Work prints: Manhattan Valley (folder 3 of 3), 1981; 65 items (Box 35, Folder 10)
      - Work prints: Manhattan Valley (1), 1981; 28 items (Box 35, Folder 11)
      - Work prints: Manhattan Valley (2) (folder 1 of 5), 1981; 40 items (Box 35, Folder 12)
      - Work prints: Manhattan Valley (2) (folder 2 of 5), 1981; 40 items (Box 35, Folder 13)
      - Work prints: Manhattan Valley (2) (folder 3 of 5), 1981; 40 items (Box 35, Folder 14)
      - Work prints: Manhattan Valley (2) (folder 4 of 5), 1981; 40 items (Box 35, Folder 15)
      - Work prints: Manhattan Valley (2) (folder 5 of 5), 1981; 44 items (Box 35, Folder 16)
      - Boricua College, contact sheets NY 111-118, 1989 January; 8 items (Box 36, Folder 1)
      - Work prints: Boricua Graduation, 1974; 22 items (Box 36, Folder 2)
      - Work prints: Boricua College (1) (folder 1 of 5), 1980; 40 items (Box 36, Folder 3)
      - Work prints: Boricua College (1) (folder 2 of 5), 1980; 40 items (Box 36, Folder 4)
      - Work prints: Boricua College (1) (folder 3 of 5), 1980; 40 items (Box 36, Folder 5)
      - Work prints: Boricua College (1) (folder 4 of 5), 1980; 40 items (Box 36, Folder 6)
      - Work prints: Boricua College (1) (folder 5 of 5), 1980; 11 items (Box 36, Folder 7)
      - Work prints: Boricua College (2) (folder 1 of 3), 1980; 40 items (Box 36, Folder 8)
      - Work prints: Boricua College (2) (folder 2 of 3), 1980; 40 items (Box 36, Folder 9)
      - Work prints: Boricua College (2) (folder 3 of 3), 1980; 24 items (Box 36, Folder 10)
      - Work prints: Boricua College (3), 1980; 56 items (Box 36, Folder 11)
      - United Bronx Parents, MLK Memorial, South Bronx, contact sheets NY 119-132, 1981 January; 14 items (Box 36, Folder 12)
      - Work prints: United Bronx Parents, MLK Memorial, South Bronx, 1981 January; 118 items (Box 36, Folder 13)
      - Work prints: United Bronx Parents, MLK Event, Bronx (folder 1 of 4), 1980; 40 items (Box 36, Folder 14)
      - Work prints: United Bronx Parents, MLK Event, Bronx (folder 2 of 4), 1980; 40 items (Box 36, Folder 15)
      - Work prints: United Bronx Parents, MLK Event, Bronx (folder 3 of 4), 1980; 40 items (Box 36, Folder 16)
      - Work prints: United Bronx Parents, MLK Event, Bronx (folder 4 of 4), 1980; 35 items (Box 36, Folder 17)
      - Museo del Barrio, 3 Kings Day, East Harlem, contact sheets NY 38-54, 1981 January 6; 17 items (Box 37, Folder 1)
      - Work prints: Museo del Barrio, 3 Kings Day, East Harlem, 1981 January 6; 128 items (Box 37, Folder 2)
      - Work prints: Museo del Barrio, 3 Kings Day, East Harlem (1) (folder 1 of 2), 1981 January 6; 46 items (Box 37, Folder 3)
      - Work prints: Museo del Barrio, 3 Kings Day, East Harlem (1) (folder 2 of 2), 1981 January 6; 34 items (Box 37, Folder 4)
      - Work prints: Museo del Barrio, 3 Kings Day, East Harlem (2) (folder 1 of 3), 1981 January 6; 50 items (Box 37, Folder 5)
      - Work prints: Museo del Barrio, 3 Kings Day, East Harlem (2) (folder 2 of 3), 1981 January 6; 50 items (Box 37, Folder 6)
      - Work prints: Museo del Barrio, 3 Kings Day, East Harlem (2) (folder 3 of 3), 1981 January 6; 57 items (Box 37, Folder 7)
      - El Puente - A Documentary, Williamsburg, Brooklyn, contact sheets 1-25, 1984; 25 items (Box 37, Folder 8)
      - Puerto Rican Legal Defense Fund, contact sheets PRLD 1-10, 17-36, 2C, 5C-10C, 1982; 37 items (Box 37, Folder 9)
  - Ohio, 1979-1980; 66 items
    - Finished Prints, 1979; 1 prints
      - Making a point: Meeting at the Spanish-American committee to discuss a meeting with the mayor, Cleveland, 1979 (Box 39, Image RL.00367-P-0263)
    - Contact Sheets and Work Prints, 1980; 65 items
      - Work Prints: Lorain, Ohio, 1980; 9 items (Box 37, Folder 10)
      - Work Prints: Ricky Ortiz, Lorain, Ohio, 1980; 15 items (Box 37, Folder 11)
      - Work Prints: Cleveland, 1980; 41 items (Box 37, Folder 12)
  - Pennsylvania, 1979-1982; 2066 items
    - Finished Prints, 1979-1982; 20 prints
      - Cook's boy, Kennett Square, Pennsylvania mushroom house, 1981 (Box 52, Image RL.00367-P-0264)
        Image dimensions: 7 1/2 x 11 inches; mount dimensions: 7 1/2 x 11 inches
      - Mushroom farm crew chief, Kennett Square, 1981 (Box 38, Image RL.00367-P-0265)
      - Kennett Square, circa 1980 (Box 38, Image RL.00367-P-0266)
      - Ricardo Molina, welding trainee, Lancaster (Print 73), 1981 (Box 38, Image RL.00367-P-0267)
        Image dimensions: 7 1/2 x 11 inches; mount dimensions: 10 x 13 inches
      - Margarita at bilingual class, Reading, 1982 (Box 38, Image RL.00367-P-0268)
      - Walter, mushroom worker organizer, Kennett Square, 1981 (Box 39, Image RL.00367-P-0269)
        Image dimensions: 9 x 13 3/8 inches; sheet dimensions: 11 x 15 3/8 inches
      - Gumercindo at mushroom farm, Kennett Square (Print 59), 1981 (Box 39, Image RL.00367-P-0270)
      - Manuel and Hazel Molina. He is a native of Puerto Rico and a permanent worker at a mushroom farm; She is a self-described hill-billy, Kennett Square (Print 75a), 1981 (Box 39, Image RL.00367-P-0271)
        Image dimensions: 7 x 11 inches; mount dimensions: 13 x 16 inches
      - Marcelino Martinez, foreman at mushroom farm, Kennett Square (Print 137), 1981 (Box 39, Image RL.00367-P-0272)
        Image dimensions: 10 3/4 x 7 1/2 inches; mount dimensions: 16 x 13 inches
      - Angelita Inizarry, migrant agricultural worker, Kennett Square (Print 57), 1981 (Box 39, Image RL.00367-P-0273)
      - Angelita Inizarry, migrant agricultural worker, Kennett Square (Print 57), 1981 (Box 39, Image RL.00367-P-0274)
      - Manuel Molina, mushroom worker, outside blockhouse where mushrooms are grown, 1981 (Box 39, Image RL.00367-P-0275)
        Image dimensions: 7 3/4 x 11 inches; mount dimensions: 13 x 16 inches
      - Manuel and Hazel Molina with two children in their house, 1981 (Box 39, Image RL.00367-P-0276)
        Image dimensions: 7 3/4 x 10 3/4 inches; mount dimensions: 13 x 16 inches
      - Margarita Quinones, outreach worker for LA Comunidad Hispana, 1981 (Box 39, Image RL.00367-P-0277)
      - Cuco, outside fenced-in hardball court. "We fixed it up and they fenced us out," Harrisburg (Print 184), 1979 (Box 40, Image RL.00367-P-0278)
        Image dimensions: 9 x 13 1/4 inches; mount dimensions: 14 x 19 inches
      - Cuco and friend, Harrisburg (Print 7), 1979 (Box 40, Image RL.00367-P-0279)
      - Kennett Square, 1981 (Box 40, Image RL.00367-P-0280)
      - Philadelphia (Print 214), 1982 (Box 40, Image RL.00367-P-0281)
        Image dimensions: 9 x 13 5/8 inches; mount dimensions: 14 x 19 inches
      - Welding instructor, Lancaster, 1981 (Box 54, Image RL.00367-P-0323)
        Image dimensions: 12 1/8 x 17 7/8 inches; mount dimensions: 20 x 24 inches
      - Manuel Molina, mushroom worker, outside blockhouse where mushrooms are grown, Kennett Square, 1981 (Box 55, Image RL.00367-P-0327)
        Image dimensions: inches; mount dimensions: 20 x 24 inches
    - Contact Sheets and Work Prints, 1979-1981; 2046 items
      - Lancaster, Reading, contact sheets PA 66-88, missing 71, 73, 83, circa 1980; 20 items (Box Unknown, Folder Unknown)
      - Work prints: Skills training, Lancaster, circa 1980 (Box Unknown, Folder Unknown)
      - Work prints: Welding training, Lancaster (1), circa 1980; 43 items (Box 41, Folder 1)
      - Work prints: Welding training, Lancaster (2) (folder 1 of 2), 1980; 50 items (Box 41, Folder 2)
      - Work prints: Welding training, Lancaster (2) (folder 2 of 2), 1980; 9 items (Box 41, Folder 3)
      - Work prints: Bilingual class, Reading (folder 1 of 2), 1980; 50 items (Box 41, Folder 4)
      - Work prints: Bilingual class, Reading (folder 2 of 2), 1980; 30 items (Box 41, Folder 5)
      - Work prints: Bilingual program, Reading (folder 1 of 4), 1980; 40 items (Box 41, Folder 6)
      - Work prints: Bilingual program, Reading (folder 2 of 4), 1980; 40 items (Box 41, Folder 7)
      - Work prints: Bilingual program, Reading (folder 3 of 4), 1980; 40 items (Box 41, Folder 8)
      - Work prints: Bilingual program, Reading (folder 4 of 4), 1980; 12 items (Box 41, Folder 9)
      - Work prints: Bilingual program, Reading, 1981; 33 items (Box 41, Folder 10)
      - Work prints: The clock lesson, Reading, 1981; 22 items (Box 41, Folder 11)
      - Harrisburg and Lancaster, contact sheets PRD 20, 22-25, 1979 December; 5 items (Box 41, Folder 12)
      - Work prints: Planning Grant (folder 1 of 16), 1979-1980; 40 items (Box 41, Folder 13)
      - Planning Grant (folder 2 of 16), 1979-1980; 40 items (Box 41, Folder 14)
      - Planning Grant (folder 3 of 16), 1979-1980; 40 items (Box 41, Folder 15)
      - Planning Grant (folder 4 of 16), 1979-1980; 40 items (Box 41, Folder 16)
      - Planning Grant (folder 5 of 16), 1979-1980; 40 items (Box 41, Folder 17)
      - Planning Grant (folder 6 of 16), 1979-1980; 46 items (Box 41, Folder 18)
      - Planning Grant (folder 7 of 16), 1979-1980; 43 items (Box 41, Folder 19)
      - Planning Grant (folder 8 of 16), 1979-1980; 50 items (Box 41, Folder 20)
      - Planning Grant (folder 9 of 16), 1979-1980; 46 items (Box 42, Folder 1)
      - Planning Grant (folder 10 of 16), 1979-1980; 40 items (Box 42, Folder 2)
      - Planning Grant (folder 11 of 16), 1979-1980; 40 items (Box 42, Folder 3)
      - Planning Grant (folder 12 of 16), 1979-1980; 40 items (Box 42, Folder 4)
      - Planning Grant (folder 13 of 16), 1979-1980; 46 items (Box 42, Folder 5)
      - Planning Grant (folder 14 of 16), 1979-1980; 50 items (Box 42, Folder 6)
      - Planning Grant (folder 15 of 16), 1979-1980; 50 items (Box 42, Folder 7)
      - Planning Grant (folder 16 of 16), 1979-1980; 36 items (Box 42, Folder 8)
      - Harrisburg, Lancaster, Avondale, Reading, Kennett Square, contact sheets PA 33-65, missing 53-58, 61, 63, 1981 June; 25 items (Box 42, Folder 9)
      - Work prints: Flower nursery (1), 1981; 32 items (Box 42, Folder 10)
      - Work prints: Flower nursery (2), 1981; 29 items (Box 42, Folder 11)
      - Work prints: Kennett Square (folder 1 of 2), 1981; 41 items (Box 42, Folder 12)
      - Work prints: Kennett Square (folder 2 of 2), 1981; 27 items (Box 42, Folder 13)
      - Work prints: Angel Hernandez, mushroom worker, Kennett Square (folder 1 of 2), 1981; 48 items (Box 42, Folder 14)
      - Work prints: Angel Hernandez, mushroom worker, Kennett Square (folder 2 of 2), 1981; 8 items (Box 42, Folder 15)
      - Work prints: Mushrooms, Kennett Square (folder 1 of 2), 1981; 40 items (Box 42, Folder 16)
      - Work prints: Mushrooms, Kennett Square (folder 2 of 2), 1981; 20 items (Box 42, Folder 17)
      - Work prints: Mushroom workers, Kennett Square (folder 1 of 3), 1981; 40 items (Box 42, Folder 18)
      - Work prints: Mushroom workers, Kennett Square (folder 2 of 3), 1981; 49 items (Box 43, Folder 1)
      - Work prints: Mushroom workers, Kennett Square (folder 3 of 3), 1981 June; 39 items (Box 43, Folder 2)
      - Harrisburg, contact sheets PA 1-32, missing 10, 1981; 32 items (Box 43, Folder 3)
      - Work prints: Centro de Vida, Drug Abuse Prevention, Harrisburg (1) (folder 1 of 3), 1981; 50 items (Box 43, Folder 4)
      - Work prints: Centro de Vida, Drug Abuse Prevention, Harrisburg (1) (folder 2 of 3), 1981; 50 items (Box 43, Folder 5)
      - Work prints: Centro de Vida, Drug Abuse Prevention, Harrisburg (1) (folder 3 of 3), 1981; 41 items (Box 43, Folder 6)
      - Work prints: Centro de Vida, Drug Abuse Prevention, Harrisburg (2), 1981; 26 items (Box 43, Folder 7)
      - Work prints: Centro de Vida, Grupo Folklorico (1), 1981; 35 items (Box 43, Folder 8)
      - Work prints: Centro de Vida, Grupo Folklorico (2), 1981; 24 items (Box 43, Folder 9)
      - Work prints: Centro de Vida, ESL Program (1), 1981; 36 items (Box 43, Folder 10)
      - Work prints: Centro de Vida, ESL Program (2) (folder 1 of 3), 1981; 50 items (Box 43, Folder 11)
      - Work prints: Centro de Vida, ESL Program (2) (folder 2 of 3), 1981; 50 items (Box 43, Folder 12)
      - Work prints: Centro de Vida, ESL Program (2) (folder 3 of 3), 1981; 40 items (Box 43, Folder 13)
      - Work prints: Centro de Vida, ESL Program (3), 1981; 23 items (Box 43, Folder 14)
      - Work prints: Centro de Vida, ESL Program (4), 1981; 47 items (Box 43, Folder 15)
      - Work prints: Centro de Vida, ESL Program (5) (folder 1 of 2), 1981; 41 items (Box 43, Folder 16)
      - Work prints: Centro de Vida, ESL Program (5) (folder 2 of 2), 1981; 22 items (Box 43, Folder 17)
  - Puerto Rico, 1979-1983; 1482 items
    - Finished Prints, 1980-1983; 14 prints
      - Las Piedras, circa 1981 (Box 38, Image RL.00367-P-0282)
        Image dimensions: 6 x 8 5/8 inches; mount dimensions: 11 x 14 inches
      - Canary, 1981 (Box 38, Image RL.00367-P-0283)
      - Juncos, 1981 (Box 38, Image RL.00367-P-0284)
      - Angel Rosano, returned migrant, after a lifetime in the South Bronx, at home with his hens, Camuy (Print 205), 1981 (Box 44, Image RL.00367-P-0285)
        Image dimensions: 11 1/4 x 7 1/2 inches; mount dimensions: 16 x 13
      - Destiny Crew, children of returned migrants, at their "hot corners" at Roman Power High School, Las Piedras (Print 199), 1981 (Box 44, Image RL.00367-P-0286)
        Image dimensions: 7 5/8 x 11 1/4 inches; mount dimensions: 13 x 16
      - El Dueno de la Plaza, Humacao (Print 101), 1981 (Box 44, Image RL.00367-P-0287)
      - Manuel Garcia, returned migrant and fourth generation fisherman, Luguillo (Print 82), 1981 (Box 44, Image RL.00367-P-0288)
        Image dimensions: 11 1/2 x 7 5/8 inches; mount dimensions: 16 x 13 inches
      - Puerto Rico, 1982 (Box 45, Image RL.00367-P-0289)
        Image dimensions: 11 7/8 x 16 7/8 inches; sheet dimensions: 16 x 19 7/8 inches
      - Ismael and Ana Aponte, returned migrants, after 30 years in Patterson, NJ, at their new home in Barrio Pasto Seco, Rio Piedras (Print 39), 1981 (Box 45, Image RL.00367-P-0290)
        Image dimensions: 7 5/8 x 11 inches; mount dimensions: 16 x 20
      - Ismael Aponte, Jr., native of Patterson, NJ, son of returned migrants, at home in Barrio Pasto Seco, Las Piedras (Print 12), 1981 (Box 45, Image RL.00367-P-0291)
        Image dimensions: 13 1/2 x 9 inches; mount dimensions: 20x16
      - Jeanette and Danny Martinez and family, returned migrants, Maunabo (Print 124), 1981 (Box 45, Image RL.00367-P-0292)
        Image dimensions: 13 1/2 x 8 3/4 inches; mount dimensions: 20 x 16 inches
      - Puerto Rico: Barrio Tokio, San Juan, 1980 (Box 45, Image RL.00367-P-0293)
        Image dimensions: 9 x 13 3/8 inches; mount dimensions: 14 x 19
      - Puerto Rico: Rosa Santiago, returned migrant, after 16 years in Lorain, Ohio. Barrio la Pica, Maunabo (Print 16), 1981 (Box 45, Image RL.00367-P-0294)
        Image dimension: 9 x 13 inches; mount dimensions: 14 x 19 inches
      - Puerto Rico: Avelino Reyes, returned migrant, with his cattle. Las Piedras (Print 177), 1981 (Box 45, Image RL.00367-P-0295)
        Image dimensions: 8 3/4 x 13 3/8; mout dimensions: 14 x 19 inches
    - Contact Sheets and Work Prints, 1981; 1468 items
      - Returning migrants, Puerto Rico, contact sheets 2-49 (missing 7, 16, 39), 1981; 45 items (Box 46, Folder 1)
      - Returning migrants, Puerto Rico, contact sheets 50-74, 1981; 25 items (Box 46, Folder 2)
      - Returning migrants, Puerto Rico, contact sheets 75-92, 1981; 18 items (Box 46, Folder 3)
      - Work prints: Returning migrants (folder 1 of 8), 1981 March; 83 items (Box 46, Folder 4)
      - Work prints: Returning migrants (folder 2 of 8), 1981 March; 68 items (Box 46, Folder 5)
      - Work prints: Returning migrants (folder 3 of 8), 1981 March; 61 items (Box 46, Folder 6)
      - Work prints: Returning migrants (folder 4 of 8), 1981 March; 71 items (Box 46, Folder 7)
      - Work prints: Returning migrants (folder 5 of 8), 1981 March; 129 items (Box 46, Folder 8)
      - Work prints: Returning migrants (folder 6 of 8), 1981 March; 84 items (Box 46, Folder 9)
      - Work prints: Returning migrants (folder 7 of 8), 1981 March; 58 items (Box 46, Folder 10)
      - Work prints: Returning migrants (folder 8 of 8), 1981 March; 122 items (Box 47, Folder 1)
      - Work Prints: The Returned Migrants (folder 1 of 17), 1981; 42 items (Box 47, Folder 2)
      - Work Prints: The Returned Migrants (folder 2 of 17), 1981; 40 items (Box 47, Folder 3)
      - Work Prints: The Returned Migrants (folder 3 of 17), 1981; 41 items (Box 47, Folder 4)
      - Work Prints: The Returned Migrants (folder 4 of 17), 1981; 50 items (Box 47, Folder 5)
      - Work Prints: The Returned Migrants (folder 5 of 17), 1981; 40 items (Box 47, Folder 6)
      - Work Prints: The Returned Migrants (folder 6 of 17), 1981; 40 items (Box 47, Folder 7)
      - Work Prints: The Returned Migrants (folder 7 of 17), 1981; 40 items (Box 47, Folder 8)
      - Work Prints: The Returned Migrants (folder 8 of 17), 1981; 41 items (Box 47, Folder 9)
      - Work Prints: The Returned Migrants (folder 9 of 17), 1981; 40 items (Box 47, Folder 10)
      - Work Prints: The Returned Migrants (folder 10 of 17), 1981; 47 items (Box 47, Folder 11)
      - Work Prints: The Returned Migrants (folder 11 of 17), 1981; 40 items (Box 47, Folder 12)
      - Work Prints: The Returned Migrants (folder 12 to 17), 1981; 40 items (Box 47, Folder 13)
      - Work Prints: The Returned Migrants (folder 13 of 17), 1981; 49 items (Box 47, Folder 14)
      - Work Prints: The Returned Migrants (folder 14 of 17), 1981; 40 items (Box 47, Folder 15)
      - Work Prints: The Returned Migrants (folder 15 of 17), 1981; 40 items (Box 47, Folder 16)
      - Work Prints: The Returned Migrants (folder 16 of 17), 1981; 40 items (Box 47, Folder 17)
      - Work Prints: The Returned Migrants (folder 17 of 17), 1981; 25 items (Box 48, Folder 1)
      - Work Prints: No known titles, 1981; 9 items (Box 48, Folder 2)
  - Washington, D.C., 1973-1984; 2; 719 items
    - Finished Prints, 1973-1984; 3; 9 prints
      - Washington DC: Hispanic Festival, 1981 (Box 38, Image RL.00367-P-0296)
        Image dimensions: 7 5/8 x 11 1/8 inches; sheet dimensions: 11 x 14 inches
      - Washington DC: Hispanic Festival, 1982 (Box 38, Image RL.00367-P-0297)
        Image dimensions: 9 x 13 1/2; sheet dimension 11 x 14 inches
      - Washington DC: Hispanic Festival, 1982 (Box 38, Image RL.00367-P-0298)
      - Washington DC: Hispanic Festival, 1983 (Box 38, Image RL.00367-P-0299)
        Image dimensions: 13 3/8 x 9 inches; sheet dimensions: 14 x 11 inches
      - Washington DC: Hispanic Festival, 1984 (Box 38, Image RL.00367-P-0300)
      - Washington DC: Hispanic Festival, 1984 (Box 38, Image RL.00367-P-0301)
      - Young man with Puerto Rico t-shirt, Solidarity Day demonstration (Print 98), 1981 (Box 49, Image RL.00367-P-0302)
        Image dimensions: 13 3/8 x 9 1/8 inches; mount dimensions: 20 x 16 inches
      - Puerto Rican "Home Town" contingent, Hispanic Festival, 1982 (Box 49, Image RL.00367-P-0303)
      - Washington, D.C., 1973 (Box 55, Image RL.00367-P-0328)
        Image dimensions: 14 3/4 x 20 inches; mount dimensions: 22 x 28 inches
    - Contact Sheets and Work Prints, 1981-1982; 710 items
      - Hispanic Festival, contact sheets 1-34, 1982; 35 items (Box 48, Folder 3)
      - Work Prints: Hispanic Festival (1), circa 1981; 31 items (Box 48, Folder 4)
      - Work Prints: Hispanic Festival (2) (folder 1 of 4), circa 1981; 50 items (Box 48, Folder 5)
      - Work Prints: Hispanic Festival (2) (folder 2 of 4), circa 1981; 50 items (Box 48, Folder 6)
      - Work Prints: Hispanic Festival (2) (folder 3 of 4), circa 1981; 50 items (Box 48, Folder 7)
      - Work Prints: Hispanic Festival (2) (folder 4 of 4), circa 1981; 26 items (Box 48, Folder 8)
      - Work Prints: Hispanic Festival (folder 1 of 2), circa 1982; 40 items (Box 48, Folder 9)
      - Work Prints: Hispanic Festival (folder 2 of 2), circa 1982; 23 items (Box 48, Folder 10)
      - Work Prints: Solidarity, DC (folder 1 of 3), 1981; 50 items (Box 48, Folder 11)
      - Work Prints: Solidarity, DC (folder 2 of 3), 1981; 50 items (Box 48, Folder 12)
      - Work Prints: Solidarity, DC (folder 3 of 3), 1981; 47 items (Box 48, Folder 13)
      - Work Prints: Solidarity Demo DC (folder 1 of 3), 1981; 40 items (Box 48, Folder 14)
      - Work Prints: Solidarity Demo DC (folder 2 of 3), 1981; 40 items (Box 48, Folder 15)
      - Work Prints: Solidarity Demo DC (folder 3 of 3), 1981; 25 items (Box 48, Folder 16)
      - Work Prints: Solidarity Day DC (folder 1 of 4), 1981; 40 items (Box 50, Folder 1)
      - Work Prints: Solidarity Day DC (folder 2 of 4), 1981; 40 items (Box 50, Folder 2)
      - Work Prints: Solidarity Day DC (folder 3 of 4), 1981; 40 items (Box 50, Folder 3)
      - Work Prints: Solidarity Day DC (folder 4 of 4), 1981; 33 items (Box 50, Folder 4)
  - Wisconsin, 1983; 131 items
    - Finished Prints, 1983; 2 prints
      - Boxing program at Centro Unido, Milwaukee (Print 218), 1983 (Box 49, Image RL.00367-P-0304)
        Image dimensions: 8 x 13 3/4 inches; mount dimensions: 16 x 20 inches
      - Milwaukee, 1980 (Box 38, Image RL.00367-P-0305)
        Image dimensions: 7 1/2 x 11 1/8 inches; sheet dimensions: 11 x 14 inches
    - Contact Sheets and Work Prints, 1979-1983; 129 items
      - Milwaukee, contact sheets 1-12, 1983; 13 items (Box 50, Folder 1)
      - Work Prints: Milwaukee, 1980; 30 items (Box 50, Folder 2)
      - Planning grant, NEH Milwaukee, contact sheets PRD 1-6, 1979; 6 items (Box 50, Folder 3)
      - Planning grant, NEH, contact sheets PRD 7-47 (missing 12, 13, 20, 22-25, 42), 1979 December-1980 May; 34 items (Box 50, Folder 4)
      - Planning grant, NEH, contact sheets PRD 49-75 (missing 50, 74), 1979 December-1980 May; 26 items (Box 50, Folder 5)
      - Planning grant, NEH, contact sheets PRD 76-95, 1979 December-1980 May; 20 items (Box 50, Folder 6)
  - Additional Puerto Rican Finished Prints, Contact Sheets and Work Prints, 1979-1989; 759 items
    - Additional small finished prints, 1980s; 17 prints (Box 52)
      Sheet dimensions: 8 1/12 x 11 inches
    - Additional work prints, 1979-1983; 20 prints (Box 50)
    - Additional work prints, 1979-1983; 13 prints (Box 51)
- Other Photographic Work, 1954-1974; 10 prints
  Images in this series are either single prints that stem from other bodies of work, or could not be positively connected with a project in the collection. The focus is on street photography and portraiture. One of the earliest works in the collection is found here: a 1954 image taken on Rockaway Avenue in Brooklyn.
  - Finished Prints
    - Chinese laundry, Blake Avenue, East New York, 1964 (Box 38, Image RL. 00367-P-0306)
      Image dimensions: 8 1/8 x 12 inches; mount dimensions: 8 1/8 x 12 inches
    - East New York, 1964 (Box 38, Image RL. 00367-P-0307)
      Image dimensions: 13 3/8 x 9 inches; sheet dimensions: 14 x 11
    - Rose! - Death Car, Rochester, New York, 1974 (Box 53, Image RL. 00367-P-0308)
    - Rockaway Avenue, Brooklyn, New York, 1954 (Box 53, Image RL. 00367-P-0309)
      Image dimensions: 11 x 17 7/8 inches; sheet dimensions: 16 x 20 inches
    - Woman and child in window, Brooklyn, New York, 1963 (Box 53, Image RL. 00367-P-0310)
    - Central Park, New York, 1960 (Box 53, Image RL. 00367-P-0311)
    - No known title, undated (Box 53, Image RL. 00367-P-0312)
      Image dimensions: 11 3/8 x 17 inches; sheet dimensions: 16 x 20 inches
    - Man by a fence, Washington, D.C., 1975 (Box 54, Image RL. 00367-P-0324)